Heroes are born when bullets fly,when earth
explodes,when cannons roar...When trumpets fade
When Trumpets Fade is a drama, war, tv movie film directed by John Irvin.
In WWII Western Germany, Private David Manning reluctantly leaves behind a mortally wounded fellow soldier and searches for survivors
from his platoon, only to learn from commanding officer Captain Pritchett that they have all been killed in action.
Despite requesting a discharge on the grounds of mental disability, Manning is
promoted to sergeant and assigned to lead a new platoon of young inductees.
Manning, played by Ron Eldard.
Warren, played by Zak Orth.
Medic Chamberlain, played by Frank Whaley.
Sgt. Talbot, played by Dylan Bruno.
Lonnie, played by Devon Gummersall.
Despin, played by Dan Futterman.
When Trumpets Fade is a 1998 HBO television movie directed by John Irvin and
starring Ron Eldard, Frank Whaley, Zak Orth, and Dylan Bruno.
First released on June 27, 1998, the film is set in World War
II during the Battle of the Hürtgen Forest.
The film explores themes of france, nazi, world war ii, infantry, us army.
The tone is emotional.